RAYMOND BELL

Dallas, TX 75208 | Phone: 757.256.9950 | Email: rcarlb2@gmail.com GitHub: <u>github.com/G6-2Flyy</u> | Portfolio: <u>rbell-portfolio.netlify.app</u>

SUMMARY

Data Analyst with MERN stack skills and 20 years of experience in operations, logistics, and production management. Former decorated military officer with prior secret clearance and a passion for transforming large data to create web-based applications, visualizations and dashboards to drive business decision-making.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, JavaScript ES6+, jQuery, R, SQL, HTML5, CSS

Tools: MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQlite, SQLAlchemy, AWS, Flask, Tableau, Seaborn, Plotly, Matplotlib, TensorFlow, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Plotly, Leaflet.js, Scikit-Learn, Jupyter Notebook, React, Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, GraphQL/Apollo, Insomnia, Bootstrap, Visual Paradigm, Visio, GitHub, Jest.js

Skills: Data Modeling, Data Analytics, Data Visualization, Data Processing, Database

Management, Web Development, Machine Learning

Other: Microsoft Office Suite, SAP, Mini-tab, Project Management, Lean Six-Sigma

PROJECTS

Tech-E

https://still-fortress-07413-3ec76e5ba3ea.herokuapp.com

- Summary: Tech-E is an e-commerce website created to provide consumers an alternate online option to purchase a wide range of tech products.
- Role: Back-end development, including server, models, resolvers, and typedefs
- Tools: React.js, Node.js, Tailwind CSS, MongoDB, Stripe, GraphQL/Apollo, JWT

STAR

https://quiet-spire-24074-96c577a8c013.herokuapp.com

- Summary: STAR is a full-stack web-based social media application designed to allow users to create, post, share, and interact with multimedia content.
- Role: Back-end development, including routes, models, photos, and video integration
- Tools: Node.js, Handlebars.js, BCrypt.js, Multer, Cloudinary, Tailwind CSS

Russia's Invasion of Ukraine

https://g6-2flyy.github.io/Invasion Of Ukraine/

- Summary: This project includes collaborative analysis of a data set that tracks all the different war incidents in Ukraine over the past year for interesting patterns and insights.
- Role: Data cleaning, data wrangling, and filtering to create responsive data visualizations
- Tools: CSS, Plotly, Leaflet.js, Pandas, NumPy, Highcharts, Apexcharts.js

SILICON PRAIRIE BANK

https://rbell-silicon-praire-bank.onrender.com/

- Summary: SPB is a web application that uses a machine learning model to determine consumer loan and credit card application approvals.
- Role: Data cleaning, data wrangling, data visualization, and machine learning models
- Tools: Pandas, CSS, Flask, Tableau, TensorFlow

EXPERIENCE

CONTINUING CAREER EDUCATION

May 2020-Present Dallas, TX

- Full Stack Coding | Data Science | MBA
 - Completed two intensive programs focused on attaining technical programming skills
 - Finalizing requirements for MBA and leveraging coding and data science skills to enhance business analytics concentration

AMAZON Mar 2018-Apr 2020

Analyst, E-Commerce

Farmers Branch, TX

- Partnered with site leadership to apply critical thinking skills and analytical methods to achieve business goals and objectives
- Re-engineered business processes and trained over 100 new hires resulting in faster product delivery and increased order completion percentages

LEAR CORPORATION

Jul 2014-Aug 2015

Quality Manager, Automotive

Arlington, TX

- Used diagnostic software for functional testing, calibration, and defect resolution
- Applied quantitative and qualitative analytical methods to generate key performance data inputs into Quality Management Systems to ensure stakeholder satisfaction

KRAFT- HEINZ Aug 2013-Jun 2014

Production Manager, Consumer Packaged Goods

Garland, TX

- Consistently acknowledged for achieving safety, quality, and cost KPIs for one of the largest food and beverage companies in the world
- Analyzed company workflow design and applied Agile Methodologies (ILSS) to reduce product changeover time by 75% resulting in adoption as new standard for the business

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

THE J.M. SMUCKER COMPANY, Operations Manager, Consumer Packaged Goods

• Managed end-to-end product supply chain for the Folgers Instant Coffee Business Unit

DELL, INC., Operations Manager, **Technology**

Managed computer system development process for largest Manufacturing Center

US ARMY, Pilot | Sr. Executive Officer | Chief Logistics Officer | Operations Officer, Aviation

Used global intelligence to execute missions to achieve joint strategic military objectives

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Coding | Southern Methodist University | Dallas, TX
Certificate, Data Science | Southern Methodist University | Dallas, TX
Master of Business Administration | The University of Texas at Dallas | Dallas, TX
Master Certificate, Lean Six Sigma | Villanova University | Villanova, PA
Bachelor of Science, Accounting | The University of Tampa | Tampa, FL